[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb6", "question": "What's the last name of Clint Eastwood's character \"Dirty\" Harry?", "answer": "Callahan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b87", "question": "What bands early album titles had a Spanish flair including \"Tres Hombres\", \"Fandango\", and \"Deguello\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a32", "question": "What is the alternative name for a guitar pick?", "answer": "Plectrum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd3eb7e83c707845b2157", "question": "Red had how many parole hearings through out the course of the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339136", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek god Apollo?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c099", "question": "What name is given to the large Russian utensil for heating and boiling water?", "answer": "Samovar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d5", "question": "What European city is known as the \"Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b217", "question": "Who was assassinated by Talmadge Hayer?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ce", "question": "What TV spy often tried to pass himself off as a salesman for the Pontiac Greeting Card Company?", "answer": "Maxwell Smart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcd", "question": "What British pop group did Bryan Ferry lead after Brian Eno's 1973 departure?", "answer": "Roxy Music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7942ff048f679a45abe1", "question": "What is the name for a virus that infects a bacteria?", "answer": "Bacteriophage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a6", "question": "What popular radio DJ was the original voice of Shaggy on \"Scooby-Doo\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e19", "question": "The show \"Ugly Betty\" is based on the telenovela \"Yo soy Betty la fea\" from what Latin American country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe378b80ada16518afdc053", "question": "Which Christmas tune was the first song performed in space?", "answer": "\"Jingle Bells\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339744", "question": "What album earned the Dixie Chicks a Grammy Award in 2007?", "answer": "Taking the Long Way", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c240", "question": "What do dragonflies eat?", "answer": "Mosquitoes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee1", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for Tom Clancy's CIA agent in the Kremlin?", "answer": "The Cardinal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66145a5bfecdd737e083a", "question": "What is the longest recorded case of the hiccups in history?", "answer": "68 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc2e56de0eb824d4052e7", "question": "Where is Blyde River Canyon, one of the largest canyons on Earth?", "answer": "South Africa -- At more than 16 miles long and 2,624 feet (26 km) deep, it is one of South Africa\u2019s most spectacular natural wonders.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe771a2eec85e375820b2fb", "question": "What does a flower worn behind a woman's right ear mean in Hawaii?", "answer": "She's single", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39a", "question": "\"Absolute zero\" is equal to zero degrees on which temperature scale?", "answer": "Kelvin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f46", "question": "What 1995 film was Robert Rodriguez's big-budget follow-up to the low-budget hit \"El Mariachi\"?", "answer": "Desperado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985b", "question": "In the movie \"Princess Mononoke\", what affliction do the Secret Engineers in Irontown have?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636d9f967692ea851899af", "question": "The surface of what is typically 70% water and 10% ice?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14621b0ee8c595b6d39bf", "question": "Which classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5f", "question": "What is a kookaburra?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbe856ce05a3942286ef2", "question": "Who recorded the song \"One of These Nights\"?", "answer": "Eagles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339979", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny's grandmother spent 20 years where?", "answer": "Soviet labour camp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da4", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"The Pelican Brief\"?", "answer": "Robert Culp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1a", "question": "Which US president was better known as \"Ike\"?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36f", "question": "What do the British call gasoline?", "answer": "Petrol", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20d", "question": "Which country were the 1920 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb10765ff7d326b622a65", "question": "Who sang \"No More Heroes\" in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Stranglers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e7", "question": "In the movie \"Three men and a Baby\" what was Michael's occupation?", "answer": "Cartoonist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce1", "question": "What term for elaborate, decorative lettering comes from the Greek meaning \"beautiful writing\"?", "answer": "Calligraphy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ed2606d333868d34d76a", "question": "What game came bundled with the first Nintendo Game Boy in America?", "answer": "Tetris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa5a573838c5c8a417f28", "question": "The red supergiant star, Betelgeuse, belongs to which constellation?", "answer": "Orion the Hunter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eb13fe83fe1f2a824bf7", "question": "Who did the German Nazi regime replace Santa Claus with?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae94c7574a5ce6b56b824c", "question": "The cobnut is the fruit of what tree?", "answer": "Hazel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8a", "question": "In Greek mythology, for who did the cyclops forge thunderbolts?", "answer": "Zeus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a906", "question": "What major river runs through Cairo?", "answer": "Nile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b11be662d71a53650fce", "question": "What is the name of the giant flame creature the Fellowship faced in the Chamber of Mazarbul?", "answer": "Balrog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008adbcf842fa4c4ba9694", "question": "What is the name of the lively Spanish dance in triple time and typically performed with castanets or tambourines?", "answer": "Fandango", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae35", "question": "What sport did Gerald Ford play at the University of Michigan?", "answer": "Football", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b8", "question": "What is Dr. Zhivago's first name?", "answer": "Yuri", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ef0108d98002fdd633dc", "question": "What is a person with numerophobia afraid of?", "answer": "Numbers or mathematics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde49fec6c6b019850c9a71", "question": "Which two nations fought for control of North America in the French and Indian War?", "answer": "France and England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899b7960d398dc9cf7a69d", "question": "In film, who is the alter ego of Daniel Hillard?", "answer": "Mrs. Doubtfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d079877e98cb97778a62", "question": "In which US state can you find the \"Garden of the Gods\"?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e1", "question": "The islands called Islas Malvinas by the Argentinians are referred to by what name by the British?", "answer": "The Falklands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b3fce662d71a53650fe7", "question": "Which European town inspired Vincent van Gogh's famous \u201cStarry Night\u201d?", "answer": "Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence, France", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f34dff048f679a45aabe", "question": "What inorganic molecule does lightning produce?", "answer": "Ozone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af29", "question": "The Kenyan terrorists fighting for independence in the 50\u2019s were known as who?", "answer": "The Mau Mau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7e", "question": "At the beginning of the Spanish-American War, what island did American soldiers invade?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f9", "question": "What is the world's largest island?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b490049076251badbeaaa", "question": "The Treaty of Ghent was the peace treaty that ended which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb54", "question": "On what mountain does Moses speak to God through the burning bush and received the Ten Commandments?", "answer": "Mt. Sinai", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2a", "question": "Who directed the 1939 movie \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Victor Fleming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32354fbf195a31e15d73ad", "question": "Which American comedian was born Benjamin Kubelsky?", "answer": "Jack Benny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fdfea4edfd43a087adcc", "question": "Disney's 2013 film \"Frozen\" was inspired by which fairy tale?", "answer": "The Snow Queen", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ed", "question": "What Harry Potter character has the patronus of a hare/bunny?", "answer": "Luna Lovegood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14e", "question": "With what nation did the US sign the Paris Peace Accords in 1973?", "answer": "North Vietnam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173d2b44491cbd7c5a17aa", "question": "What is the oldest active international airline?", "answer": "KLM Royal Dutch Airlines -- Founded in 1919, KLM is also the\u00a0oldest airline in the world\u00a0still operating under its original name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa78373838c5c8a417f39", "question": "What kind of animal is a bustard?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae26", "question": "Who did Anne Hathaway marry in 1582?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e5dffe83fe1f2a824bc6", "question": "Who was \"The Lady Bandit of Arizona\"?", "answer": "Pearl Hart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39d", "question": "What European capital celebrated its 2,000th anniversary in 1951?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b5", "question": "What was Mary\u2019s last name on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a56220565ad31a57c7cb", "question": "Which US President owned a haberdashery?", "answer": "Harry S. Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5921ff04a4edfd43a087add3", "question": "Which scientist wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hawking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7d", "question": "What is the common name for the Aurora Borealis?", "answer": "Northern lights", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b892", "question": "What is the highest score in darts from three different doubles?", "answer": "114", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae95e6574a5ce6b56b825b", "question": "What is Beethoven's sixth symphony known as?", "answer": "The Pastoral Symphony", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbc912660f0007efaba0e56", "question": "What general family are orcas in?", "answer": "Dolphins", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5f", "question": "In Britain, what kind of meat comes in rashers?", "answer": "Bacon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69a4c20565ad31a57c752", "question": "Plato thought the Lost Island of Atlantis was linked to which ancient culture?", "answer": "Minoan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda3", "question": "What Australian snack is made from the yeast extract left over from making beer?", "answer": "Vegemite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399de", "question": "Who was the only one of the six main characters on \"Friends\" to not get married at any time on the show?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b9", "question": "What was Peter Gunn's girlfriend's name?", "answer": "Edie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbe", "question": "What was meant to happen to anyone who drank from the river Lethe?", "answer": "Lost their memory", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfae", "question": "What is liquid clay used in pottery called?", "answer": "Slip", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe6", "question": "What country saw the origin of lawn tennis?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa8", "question": "\"A bushy, bushy blonde hair\u00addo\" is a line from what hit song?", "answer": "Surfin' USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b3ce01dd7bf43be5e7b5", "question": "What TV show inspired the term \"spam\" for junk email?", "answer": "\"Monty Python's Flying Circus\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3a", "question": "How long is the Le Mans endurance motor race?", "answer": "24 hours", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339875", "question": "In Disney's \"The Jungle Book\", what kind of animal is Mowgli raised by?", "answer": "Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c418", "question": "What name is given to the closest star to the Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90cf1f52800b05cac20f07", "question": "What US state receives the most annual rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e68", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Yogi Bear?", "answer": "Daws Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339916", "question": "What was the name of Vince Vaughn\u2019s gymnasium in \u201cDodgeball: A True Underdog Story\u201d?", "answer": "Average Joe's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339887", "question": "What colour did The Hulk originally start as?", "answer": "Grey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b8", "question": "Who played the alien high commander in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "John Lithgow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b99", "question": "Who is the main character in the Odyssey?", "answer": "Odysseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5b", "question": "In 1994, Mary Ramsey replaced Natalie Merchant as the lead singer for what group?", "answer": "10,000 Maniacs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a1", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after a titan of Greek myth?", "answer": "Promethium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c8", "question": "The singer Shakira comes from what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66e", "question": "Which have longer snouts - alligators or crocodiles?", "answer": "Crocodiles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c3820815febcc896f927a", "question": "What is the ninth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Sagittarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f48", "question": "What naval hobbyist produced the landmark book \"All the World's Fighting Ships\" in 1898?", "answer": "Fred T. Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338994", "question": "How many of the gifts in the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\" include humans?", "answer": "5", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e9a0bebfabb9c85d8a977", "question": "What was the birth name of Bing Crosby?", "answer": "Harry Lillis Crosby Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a548", "question": "The Chocolate Mountains are located in what desert?", "answer": "Sonoran Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be580ed5415ba52ed6f0abb", "question": "Canada's Maple Leaf national flag was introduced under which Canadian Prime Minister?", "answer": "Lester B. Pearson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c889", "question": "What is the chemical name for a dentist's \"laughing gas\"?", "answer": "Nitrous oxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d8", "question": "White creme de menthe is added to what alcohol to make a Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "Cognac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339caf", "question": "What breed of dog is McGruff?", "answer": "Bloodhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d7", "question": "Which singer had a 1964 hit with \"King of the Road\"?", "answer": "Roger Miller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ab", "question": "What kind of shop does William own in the movie \"Notting Hill\"?", "answer": "A Travel Bookstore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c94", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Quahog, Rhode Island?", "answer": "The Family Guy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a2", "question": "A rabbit punch is a blow to what part of the body?", "answer": "Neck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998a", "question": "What rocker was backed by a band called \"Crazy Horse\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fa", "question": "In what 1996 movie did Henry Winkler play the principal of Woodsboro High School?", "answer": "Scream", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a97820565ad31a57c804", "question": "Where is the \"grassy knoll\" located?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza, Dallas, Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a080", "question": "What was Captain Jean Luke Picard's favorite tea in \"Star Trek: The Next Generation\"?", "answer": "Earl Grey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb16e65ff7d326b622a6a", "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Southern hemisphere?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c674", "question": "Downy, Hairy and Pileated are species of what bird?", "answer": "Woodpecker", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0a", "question": "What author created the character of The Continental Op?", "answer": "Dashiell Hammett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51a", "question": "What tart fruit has a sweet variety called \"Meyer\"?", "answer": "Lemon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f0", "question": "What kind of oil, a product of the flax plant, is used to make most oil paints?", "answer": "Linseed oil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6b", "question": "How many individual little squares are there on a standard Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "54", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25e", "question": "What year was rapper MC Hammer born?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76ff8eec85e375820b2f1", "question": "In which city was the 2000 movie \"Gladiator\" filmed?", "answer": "Ouarzazate", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6018bcb0d96d05b23b28165a", "question": "Who was murdered along with OJ Simpson\u2019s estranged wife Nicole?", "answer": "Ronald Goldman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a79d", "question": "Pearl Harbor is located on which Hawaiian island?", "answer": "Oahu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7a", "question": "During what war was the novel \"M*A*S*H\" set?", "answer": "Korean War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3c", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The Shifting Reef\"?", "answer": "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5921fceda4edfd43a087adc5", "question": "What number is represented by \"C\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "100", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1c", "question": "What type of animal is a Borzoi?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a6", "question": "What was Betty Rubble's maiden name?", "answer": "McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774232284458f1d785441e", "question": "What church in Georgia has produced the films \"Flywheel\", \"Facing the Giants\", \"Fireproof\", \"Courageous\",and \"War Room\"?", "answer": "Sherwood Baptist Church, Albany, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5e", "question": "What are the names of the main characters of the \"Twilight\" book series?", "answer": "Bella and Edward", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ccb", "question": "What nursery rhyme character \"kissed the girls and made them cry\"?", "answer": "Georgy Porgy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea4399ff048f679a45ab83", "question": "What are the Southern Lights called?", "answer": "Aurora Australis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab99cf121a8909e5c332d3c", "question": "What actor was famous for the line \"nanoo nanoo\"?", "answer": "Robin Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfb83e003d27d341092bbc", "question": "Which country has the most embassies abroad?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9d", "question": "In what city did Rosa Parks refuse to give up her seat for a white passenger?", "answer": "Montgomery, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7351ceec85e375820b244", "question": "Who was Dwight D. Eisenhower's vice president?", "answer": "Richard M. Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b297", "question": "Under what Roman pseudonym were the Federalist Papers written?", "answer": "Publius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c851", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the endometrium?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befb", "question": "What New York Giants' bone-crushing tackle in 1985 ended quarterback Joe Thiemann's career?", "answer": "Lawrence Taylor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cfb0877e98cb97778a51", "question": "What does Machu Picchu translate to in English?", "answer": "Old mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa400bc73aa70ea0b70b06", "question": "The Pine Barrens in southern New Jersey is the supposed home of which legendary creature?", "answer": "Jersey Devil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e94cf985ea27d7a1303aecf", "question": "In what year was \"Magic: The Gathering\" first released?", "answer": "1993", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c0", "question": "In religion, the assumption of an Earthly form by a god?", "answer": "Incarnation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaf", "question": "How many hole cards is each player dealt in Texas Hold 'Em?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a79d90aac110e4167088", "question": "Under what name is Bulmers cider sold outside of Ireland?", "answer": "Magners", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7167a9e54d890926f6df", "question": "What is the family name of the ruling dynasty of Monaco?", "answer": "Grimaldi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02e", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", what is Stewie's favorite TV show?", "answer": "Jolly Farm Revue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79d", "question": "What is the only moon in our solar system to spin in a direction opposite of its planet's rotation?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b3", "question": "In The Simpsons, Bart wins first prize at the science fair by proving what?", "answer": "Hamsters can fly planes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe2", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47a", "question": "In which country is the Simpson Desert located?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0a", "question": "What is the name of Canada's national anthem?", "answer": "O Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899d1360d398dc9cf7a6a9", "question": "John F. Kennedy Airport was originally named what?", "answer": "Idlewild Airport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39e", "question": "What bird bone is known as the \"wishbone\"?", "answer": "Collarbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2d", "question": "Which band member of Blind Melon died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Shannon Hoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe521881bf59ab7d2e380e3", "question": "How many swimmers are in a medley relay team?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e2", "question": "Sleeping sickness is carried by which insect?", "answer": "Tsetse fly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9043401dd7bf43be5e873", "question": "What was the theme of the first Macy's Thanksgiving Parade?", "answer": "Mother Goose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee5", "question": "What future \"Grey's Anatomy\" costar played Sandra Oh's lover in the movie \"Under the Tuscan Sun\"?", "answer": "Kate Walsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339378", "question": "Johann Van der Smut is better known as what?", "answer": "Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba2d8874c93a3298b2136", "question": "Which Italian won the 1998 Tour de France bicycle race?", "answer": "Marco Pantani", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe909bc01dd7bf43be5e891", "question": "Named after the mallow flower, mauve is a shade of what?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92f", "question": "Where is the Track and field Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Indianapolis, Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff7c3fe2b316f4693fb67ac", "question": "What is the proper title for a person who makes pizzas in a pizzeria?", "answer": "A pizzaiolo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339143", "question": "When did Benjamin Britten's opera \"Death in Venice\" premier?", "answer": "1973", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bf", "question": "On what island was Jurassic Park located?", "answer": "Isla Nublar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d76", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Novel Without a Hero\"?", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987e", "question": "In Star Wars, what kind of a farm does Luke Skywalker grow up on?", "answer": "Moisture farm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b5", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b48", "question": "What was the two-word subtitle of the fourth \"Mission Impossible\" movie in the Tom Cruise series?", "answer": "Ghost Protocol", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a4", "question": "What director died four months before the release of his movie \"Eyes Wide Shut\"?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c312", "question": "The popular caterpillar sushi roll features unagi, the Japanese word for what type of sea creature?", "answer": "Eel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3a", "question": "What was World War I known as before World War II?", "answer": "The Great War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab2", "question": "When did college basketball introduce the 3\u00ad-point shot?", "answer": "1987", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff0eb668d7dfe168b5b3", "question": "In which country is the alcoholic drink Pulque consumed?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f6", "question": "What is the lowest land point on Earth?", "answer": "Dead Sea shore, Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91c", "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color?", "answer": "Hemoglobin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ee", "question": "Black Corinth, Muscat, and Thompson Seedless are varieties of what fruit?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339154", "question": "In \"The Saint\" series of books, what is Inspector Teal's full name?", "answer": "Claud Eustace Teal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6ba74fb6c85e9e634ff51", "question": "What branch of mathematics is named for the Latin for \"small pebble\"?", "answer": "Calculus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a10", "question": "What year was the setting for the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95487ccba3ffe45786dd", "question": "What country are you most likely to hear its residents speak Malagasy?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1c", "question": "In what 1992 movie does Jennifer Jason Leigh play a dangerous \"roommate from Hell\"?", "answer": "Single White Female", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cd", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a49", "question": "What was the real first name of the jazz performer Duke Ellington?", "answer": "Edward", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd82", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Ebirah?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f766b4e2c7fbd3896748", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d119564fea7fe947a2228d", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa551cc73aa70ea0b70b21", "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?", "answer": "Akihabara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c712", "question": "What hormone secreted by the pancreas lowers blood glucose levels in diabetics?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee2", "question": "Which war did the Treaty of Portsmouth end in 1905?", "answer": "The Russo-Japanese War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a3", "question": "In what movie does Sean Penn play a mentally challenged man?", "answer": "I Am Sam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ec", "question": "The Kung San people live in what area of Africa?", "answer": "Kalahari Desert in Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c89ce0011619dd6d415480", "question": "Under what name did Eric Cartman appear as a calculus teacher in an inner-city school in season 12?", "answer": "Eric Cartmenez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae68", "question": "Who were known by GI's in World War II as \"Hit & Muss\"?", "answer": "Hitler and Mussolini", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6e", "question": "Bangladesh is located at the apex of which Bay?", "answer": "Bay of Bengal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a630a2ebb971c1417fb96", "question": "What year did the \"Turbot War\" fishing dispute start?", "answer": "1994", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be5", "question": "What two kinds of opera do the Arts recognize?", "answer": "Comic and Grand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cb", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Little Corporal\"?", "answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2b", "question": "Who became an animated Disney megastar after replacing Oswald the Lucky Rabbit?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8cc6794b094db9158309f", "question": "What 2016 nominated short film shares a name with an animated film also released the same year?", "answer": "Sing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dbabf4f3bc4a292f8619", "question": "Which country was the first to recognize the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "France (In 1841, France opened a legation in Austin and the Republic of Texas opened an embassy in Paris.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bda", "question": "What was the name of the three-headed god that guarded the gates to Hades?", "answer": "Cerebus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a497", "question": "Which desert is found in South East Mongolia and Northern China?", "answer": "Gobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a09c20565ad31a57c797", "question": "What was the Liberty Bell originally called?", "answer": "The State House Bell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7facff048f679a45ac14", "question": "What poison is found in apple seeds?", "answer": "Cyanide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ed", "question": "What does an electroencephalogram show?", "answer": "Electrical activity in the brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909d038bb53d1af658864f9", "question": "Which Canadian Prime Minister was born on December 25, 1971?", "answer": "Justin Trudeau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59d1850d3b17032616b590fb", "question": "What 14th century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "Piers Plowman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675f432b59efe0e9417e99", "question": "What animal can dig a tunnel 300 feet long in just one night?", "answer": "A mole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1edc4145fb2946670738a", "question": "What is added to vanilla ice cream to make New Zealand\u2019s popular hokey-pokey flavor?", "answer": "Honeycomb toffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3ae6ce05a3942286ea7", "question": "What was the first James Bond title song to top the U.S. charts?", "answer": "\"A View to a Kill\" by Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003988f57a0e35c43f8389c", "question": "What female surrealist did Andre Breton call \"the sorceress who left too soon\"?", "answer": "Male surrealists almost never saw female painters as capable artists.  Varo proved them wrong with her images of women.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace5", "question": "Which Greek goddess gave her name to the city of Athens?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68e", "question": "What element\u2019s chemical symbol is \"Ni\"?", "answer": "Nickel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c5", "question": "The term \"black market\" was first used during which war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab4", "question": "What is the medical term for earwax?", "answer": "Cerumen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b1", "question": "Who became the chairman of the Truth and Reconciliation Commission in 1995?", "answer": "Archbishop Desmond Tutu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339252", "question": "What city is the setting for the movie \"Gladiator\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4a", "question": "What is a particle of light called?", "answer": "A photon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339385", "question": "In which US state does \"The Blair Witch Project\" take place in?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919d", "question": "Who was the voice of Donkey in the \"Shrek\" movie series?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951b", "question": "Who voiced Hercules in the 1997 Disney movie with the same name?", "answer": "Tate Donovan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917a", "question": "Which Philip K. Dick novelette is the movie \"Total Recall\" based on?", "answer": "We Can Remember It For You Wholesale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea48c0ff048f679a45abb3", "question": "Which electronic component can be classified as NPN or PNP?", "answer": "Transistor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d7fa2596a59cbdfbd3bd", "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes was dedicated to which god?", "answer": "Helios", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc5", "question": "Monza and Silverstone are venues for which sport?\u00a0", "answer": "Formula One Racing\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82f", "question": "What tree appears on the national flag of Lebanon?", "answer": "Cedar tree", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60c", "question": "Entomologists study what?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa80", "question": "What is the nickname for Reading, Pennsylvania?", "answer": "Pretzel City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c1", "question": "One of the Midwest's \"Quad Cities\" is named for what three-mile-long island in the Mississippi?", "answer": "Rock Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d5532b42d4a3561a9f01", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of the advertising company Francine interviews for and gets mocked at in the elevator?", "answer": "RBK&S", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338926", "question": "Who is the father of the Hulkling?", "answer": "Captain Marvel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa8", "question": "At which famous American battle was General Custer defeated by Sitting Bull?", "answer": "Little Bighorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c923", "question": "What nutrient is required by the body in order to build up muscles?", "answer": "Protein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb0", "question": "Who was the director of the FBI from 1924 to 1972?", "answer": "J. Edgar Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05b", "question": "What was the name of the place where Washington\u2019s troops encamped in the winter of 1777?", "answer": "Valley Forge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc8ceec223966ae8f8893", "question": "What term is used in describing a situation where a golfer scores 8 on a hole?", "answer": "\"Snowman\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbc", "question": "What addiction-inducing crop did Christopher Columbus discover in Cuba in 1492?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d19", "question": "In what country was composer Ludwig van Beethoven born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c256", "question": "What is the SI physical unit of dynamic viscosity?", "answer": "Pascal-second", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84c", "question": "In what country is the Nobel Peace Prize awarded?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902f", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Vulcan?", "answer": "Hephaestos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caff", "question": "The drug quinine was originally isolated from the bark of which tree?", "answer": "Cinchona", "category": "science"}]